(upbeat music)
- Hello, everyone,
welcome back to English Pot.
My name is Marco, and I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing you the
second part of Christmas Chronicles.
- Another Christmas lesson to
get you in the Christmas spirit.
- Christmas and useful language
for all of our listeners today.
- That's right, in today's lesson, we'll be
learning some great Christmas vocabulary.
- And police related vocabulary as well.
- Now, Christmas, police vocabulary,
how exactly does that fit together?
- Well, they don't.
But here at English Pot,
we can make anything
happen, so that's
why we have done this.
To be creative, to be creative.
So let's take a look at our
vocabulary preview for this lesson.
- vocabulary preview.
- In today's vocabulary preview,
we've got two words from our dialogue
that you will need to know
to understand this dialogue.
The first one is elves,
elves, elves, elves.
And this is the plural
of the word elf, elf, right?
So elves are little people,
little people with pointy hats.
- But pointy hats sense as helpers.
- Okay, so elves, elves.
Our next word is candy cane, candy cane.
Candy cane, candy cane.
So a candy cane is a traditional
Christmas candy, right?
- Yes, it's red and white.
- And kind of shaped like a J?
- Like a J, yeah.
- Okay, so it's very traditional.
- Yeah, you hang them on the tree,
and you eat them at Christmas time.
- Yes.
- He's like peppermint.
- Okay, well, I guess we're ready to
listen to our dialogue for the first time,
and it's gonna be kind of fast, but don't
worry if you don't understand everything,
because we'll come back and talk
about some of the language later.
(upbeat music)
♪ It's gonna straight to the dinner ♪
- Really, Thaws, you can't take me to jail.
Don't you know who I am?
Chris Cringle, you know?
Papa Noelle, pair Noelle!
- Bob, I'm not all that.
Shouldn't not all try it.
- Yeah, yeah, we've heard that
one before, haven't we, Joe?
- Yeah, last week we booked this
guy, who claimed to be a tooth fairy.
Can you believe that?
(laughing)
- That's Christmas Eve, and I
have all these presents to deliver.
Where's your Christmas spirit?
- What will happen while the
children wake up tomorrow,
and don't find any
gifts on their stockings?
- Sorry, buddy, your
partner, no parking zone.
You were speeding, and you have no idea.
- Besides that, even if we let you go
now, your sleigh's been impounded,
and those reindeer
were taken to the city zoo.
- Why?
This is unbelievable.
What's this world coming to?
Christmas is ruined.
- What's that up ahead?
It looks like.
- What else?
Whoa, they're shooting candy canes.
Mayday, mayday, we're under heavy attack.
We need backup.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so Santa has escaped
from the police car, eh?
- Thank God.
It's like a war over there.
They were really firing everything.
- I know, I mean, those
elves, are aggressive.
- Very aggressive.
- Okay, well, we can take a look at
some great vocabulary from this dialogue.
Why don't we start with our
language takeaway for today?
- Language takeaway.
- In today's language takeaway,
we have five really important words
that we hope you will
take away from the lesson.
- Exactly, and the
first word that we have
today is booked, booked,
booked, booked, booked.
- Booked is another way of saying.
- Arrested.
- Yeah, it's a slang word, hey?
- It's kind of slangy, yeah.
- Yeah, it's a slang word, booked.
- Okay, next word, speeding,
speeding, speeding, speeding.
- So Santa was speeding
because he was going too fast.
- Driving too fast, yeah.
- Okay.
- Going over the speed limit.
- Exactly.
Third word today is impounded.
- Impounded.
- That's when your car gets arrested.
- Your car gets arrested.
- Yeah, they take your car to car jail.
- Okay, so my car is in car jail.
I think I understand.
- It's impounded.
- Okay, so the police take my
car and I have to pay to get it out.
- Okay.
- Let's move to our next
word, ruined, ruined, ruined.
We have a few examples for us to listen
to understand the meaning of this word.
- Example one.
It's been raining for five days.
Allification is ruined.
- Example two.
- Look at this hole, you
ruined my favorite pair of jeans.
- Example three.
- Sam, you've been caught
stealing from the company.
Your chances for a promotion are ruined.
- Okay, great examples and basically
ruined means, destroy, destroy.
- Yeah, messed up, messed up, okay.
Now for our last word, back up, back up.
So now for our last word.
Okay, so now for our last word and language
takeaway, back up, back up, back up.
So back up is help, help, right?
So when you call for
back up, you call for help.
- Yeah, you see it all the time in
war, movies, police, call for back up.
- Yeah, right.
- I think though it's
important to point out
that here the pronunciation and stress
of this phrase is really important, hey?
- Yes, yes.
- You have to say back
up, back up, back up.
- Yeah.
- Both words are stressed
at about the same level, hey?
- Mm-hmm, back up.
- 'Cause if you were to stay back up.
- That means to move back.
- Exactly.
- Yeah, it's different.
So back up, back up.
- Yes.
The stress is important. - The stress.
- All right, well, you know what,
I think with those words in mind,
it's time for us to listen to
the dialogue a second time.
- Really, fellows, you
can't take me to jail.
Don't you know who I am?
Chris Cringle, you know?
Pop in the well.
Per no well.
Bob on the tallay.
Shuttin' dialogue, man.
- Yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before.
Haven't we Joe?
- Yeah, last week we booked this
guy who claimed to be the tooth fairy.
Can you believe that?
(laughs)
It's Christmas Eve and I have
all these presents to deliver.
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen when all
the children wake up tomorrow
and don't find any
gifts in their stockings?
- Side buddy, you were
poctin' a no-pocking zone.
You were speeding and you have no ID.
- Besides that, even if we let you go now,
your sleigh has been impounded and
those reindeer were taken to the city zoo.
- What?
This is unbelievable.
What's the world coming to?
Christmas is ruined.
- What's that up ahead?
It looks like elves.
Whoa, they're shootin' candy canes.
Mayday, Mayday, we are under heavy attack.
We need backup.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so without the
sound effects and without
any noise, I think it's
much more clear now, right?
- A little less dramatic, less
dramatic, but good language.
- Yes, speaking of good language,
there's some great phrases I
wanna look at in this dialogue.
And so let's do that
in putting it together.
- Putting it together.
- We have two phrases in
putting it together that we want
to show you how you can
use in many different situations.
In the dialogue, we heard this.
Last week, we booked this guy
who claimed to be a tooth fairy.
- So when you claim to be
something, you're saying that
you are something, but
it might not be true, right?
- Right, so for example, you can say,
this woman claimed to
be your wife, but she's not.
- But she's not.
- Okay, we have a few other examples
of how you can use the phrase claim to.
- Example one.
Daniel claimed to be
the son of a government
minister, but later we
found out that he was lying.
- Example two.
- The criminals came to have a gun.
- Example three.
- This man here is claiming
to know your father.
That's such a great phrase,
just by putting it together
with another verb, means something different,
but still expresses that same idea.
- Right, claim to have, she claimed
to have a baby or something.
- Yeah. - Okay.
- Okay, so let's move to our next phrase.
- Under heavy.
- So in the dialogue, they
said we're under heavy attack.
- Right.
- You can also use this phrase
in a couple of other ways.
- Example one.
- We're in the heavy attack.
- Example two.
- We're under heavy fire.
- Example three.
- The prime minister
is under heavy security.
- So if you're under heavy fire.
- Means that there's a lot of fire.
Like gunfire. - Gunfire, yeah.
- Yeah, not like fire or fire.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Okay, and if you're under heavy security.
- It means that you have a lot of security,
a lot of bodyguards or a lot of...
- Right.
- Like a prime minister or a
president will be under heavy security.
- Exactly.
- Okay.
Couple of great phrases.
- Really good phrases, and with this,
we can listen to our dialogue a third time.
(upbeat music)
- That's Christmas Eve, and I
have all these presents to deliver.
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen while
the children wake up
tomorrow and don't find
any gifts on their children.
- Yeah.
- That's the first time we've been here.
- Yeah, yeah, we've heard
that one before, haven't we Joe?
- Yeah, last week we booked this
guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy.
Can you believe that?
(laughs)
- That's Christmas Eve, and I
have all these presents to deliver.
Where's your Christmas spirit?
What will happen while the
children wake up tomorrow?
- And they're stockings.
- Sorry buddy, your
partner, no parking zone.
You were speeding, and you have no idea.
- Besides that, even if we let you go
now, your sleigh's been impounded,
and those reindeer
were taken to the city zoo.
- Why?
This is unbelievable.
Once this world coming
to Christmas is ruined.
- What's that up ahead?
It looks like elves.
Whoa, they're shooting candy canes.
Mayday, mayday, we're under
heavy attack, we need backup.
(upbeat music)
- So Marco, the police mentioned
something about the tooth fairy.
- The tooth fairy.
- I don't know, maybe some of our listeners
don't know this story
about the tooth fairy.
So can I go ahead and say it?
- Yes, go ahead.
- Okay, well, when you're
small, and you lose the tooth,
you're baby teeth.
- Yeah, you put it underneath
your pillow, and then you go to sleep.
And then in the night, the
tooth fairy comes into the house,
flies into the house,
sneaks under your
pillow, takes the tooth,
and puts money there.
- I see.
- So this is a story
that parents tell their
kids about what happens
to their baby teeth.
- And they get money exchange for it.
- Right, so I guess it takes away
the sadness of losing that tooth.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But in South America, for
example, we have the tooth mouse.
- The tooth mouse.
- Yes.
- Okay, mouse.
- How does it call it in Spanish?
- Well, in some places it's called
(speaking in foreign language)
It has a last name, that is.
- Oh, really?
- In other places, it's just called
(speaking in foreign language)
which means mouse.
- Okay, so it'd be like tooth fairy smith.
- Tooth fairy smith.
- And it's the same
thing, it's the little mouse
that comes in and steals a little tooth
from you and leaves money in exchange.
- Cool.
- Very cool. - Yeah.
- Well, we go from Santa Claus
to Guns N' Wars to the tooth fairy.
- Only an English pod.
- Exactly.
All right, guys, I hope
you enjoyed today's lesson.
If you have any questions
or comments about the
lesson, please visit our
website EnglishPod.com.
All right, well, we're out of time.
We gotta go, we've got some
Christmas shopping to do.
- Yes, Christmas shopping, so we'll see you
guys later and until then, it's goodbye.
(upbeat music)
[MUSIC PLAYING]